[MUSIC].
I'm Jacob.
I'm a Product Operations Manager
at Google.
Product Operations is not that
different from a program manager.
I've had lots of different titles.
I've been a Solutions Consultant.
I've been a Program Manager.
Now I'm in Product
Operations as a manager.
And really, it's the same set of skills:
being able to organize people, take
really complex ideas, make it simple for
people to understand, so
that our teams can then work on those.
Products Operations Manager is a
really diverse role.
Not only do we work with engineers,
we work with the product,
we work with legal, but
we're really the voice of the customer.
And so we have a really unique position
where we get to take customer feedback,
whether that's coming in
from a support channel, and
then be able to kind of work with
product to build a solution.
Process improvement is looking at
data to understand how we can make
something more effective or
cost efficient.
When we work on projects, we're always
taking a look at how we're managing things
to see if we can be better.
One example I can give is just
taking notes—seems super simple, but
a lot of times what will happen is notes
get taken, and we forget to send it out
again, we forget to send the email after so that people are updated.
So we're constantly looking at new
ways to do things like take notes.
How do we organize the skills and
the projects that we have?
So that's part of the process improvement
is definitely looking at the tools at our
disposal and
seeing if there's something new.
Continuous improvement's more a mentality
that we have on the team of constantly
pushing ourselves, even if we feel like the product is at a good place to be better.
Working with technology,
things are constantly changing,
and so we have to have that mindset of
continually trying to improve
things.
You can plan things out perfectly, or
what you think is perfect, and
there's always going to
be something to come up.
Once you get something out in the wild,
people will use the product in ways
that you didn't even think about,
and so that's where that idea of
continuous improvement comes in.
Because even when you think it's great,
you need to be able to look at it,
let your ego down, and
be able to solve those problems once you
see how people are actually using it.
It's critical to technology
because it moves so fast.
Things change so quickly.
If we aren't constantly improving
the things that we do or
looking at the processes that we have,
we're going to get behind.
We're always adding new features,
and so those always make new problems for
us to try to solve.
If you believe that what you're trying
to do is really for people, and
you forget about the numbers, you forget
about all of that stuff, you remember
that your product is going to
potentially make someone really happy or
make someone potentially more
successful in their business.
Those are the kinds of things that
really make me excited to work and
puts away all of that frustration
of the kind of lead up.